Guide to the Spanish Civil War Letters ALBA.308
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Spanish Civil War Letters
1929-1944
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jackson, Kevin
ALBA.308
0.5 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box.
This collection of Spanish Civil War Letters documents events and activities that occurred prior to and post war from 1929 to 1944. The collection is comprised of correspondence in both letter and postcard formats. The handwritten letters are from different participants and times during the war, and include written communication between soldiers and their family members; government officials; prisoners of war; and others. This collection documents particular activities of the Spanish Civil War from the personal perspectives of these individuals.
Scope and Contents
This collection of Spanish Civil War Letters consists of correspondence in both letter and postcard formats. The handwritten letters are from different participants and times during the war, and include written communication between soldiers and their family members; government officials; prisoners of war; and others. This collection documents particular activities of the Spanish Civil War from the personal perspectives of these individuals.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were purchased from Kevin Jackson in 2015; there is no previous documentation concerning the provenance of these materials before they came into the vendor's possession. The accession number associated with this purchase is 2019.022.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Postcards.; Prisoners -- Correspondence.; Correspondence.; Prisoner-of-war camps; Jackson, Kevin; Unión General de Trabajadores de España
- Postcards from Father to Son / 11th Division, 100th Brigade Battalion, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Postcards from Miguel Rico Gonzalez while Prisoner, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Letters from Republican Fighter Vicente Andres Sanchez to his Father, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Letters from Maria Villar to husband Raimundo, 1937-1940 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters from Republican Soldiers in Concentration Camps, 1929-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Letters from Republican Soldiers who became Prisoners of War, 1942-1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Letter from Jose Torres to U.G.T. Union, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Letters from Luis Rego while Prisoner at Central Prison of Astorga, Leon, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Letters from Pedro Gimeno to Father, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Letters from Jose Navarro to Regina Sanmiguel, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Letters from Maria and Marugin to son Julio, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Letter from Republican Father to Daughter, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Letter from Seizure Control Committee of U.G.T. to F.C. Suburbanes, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Letter from U.G.T. for Distribution of Footwear, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)